

Aleksandr Berezhnoy 29.12.1980 Krasnodar, Russia S berezhnoy_aa1980

L +7 999 4141041 **D**

② Berezhnoy_aa@mail.ru③ Berezhnoy Sasha

Aberezhnoy 1980

Experience

2021/01-ongoing Trainee programmer (graduate)

GeekBrains

♥ Moscow, Russia

» Java-development

>> Frontend-development

2007/01–2020/12 Analyst

Schlumberger

Moscow, Russia

» marketing & sales: market & tender campaigns analysis, research \$ reporting

» finance: investment projects dev, decomposition P&L modeling on contracts

» supply: implementation of tender procedures & inventory management (JIT), ISO standards, export/import ops, staff training

IT Skills

Java	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	
Spring									
MySQL									
HTML/CSS									
Maven									
$\operatorname{Git/Docker}$									
bash/Latex/xml/yaml									
${ m macOS/GNU/Linux(Ubuntu)}$									
Intellij IDEA/VSC/MySQLWorkbanch									

Projects

- \gg simple client-server application with the ability to authorize, log and store messages
- » stack: Java-core, io, JDBC, JavaFX, SQLite, Log4j, Maven
- » GitHub: https://github.com/Aberezhnoy1980/java-network-chat
- ## 2021/09 Network storage
 - » client-server application for exchanging files between an authorized client and server
 - » stack Java-core, JDBC, Netty, JavaFX, jackson, lombok, MySQL, Log4j, Maven
 - » GitHub: https://github.com/Aberezhnoy1980/network-storage-manager
- **#** 2021/12 Game
 - » android game
 - » stack Java-core, libGDX, Gradle
 - » GitHub: https://github.com/Aberezhnoy1980/StarGame
- ## 2022/06 Spring Market
 - » A complete MVC project for an online store, including using microservice architecture
 - » stack Java-core, MySQL, Maven, Stream API, Thymeleaf, Spring Boot, Spring REST API, Spring data JPA, jackson, Spring security, hibernate ORM, liquibase, NodeJS & Angular, redis, Spring Integration, Docker, RabbitMQ, Selenium & Cucumber
 - \gg GitHub: https://github.com/Aberezhnoy1980/eshop_project

Education

2021/01-present

Java development

GeekBrains

♀ Moscow, Russia

- » theoretical and practical experience:
 - » Java core: OOP, classes/enums/interfaces/annotation, exceptions, multithreading, generics, collections, GUI (JavaFX & Swing), database & networking basics, testing, reflection API. Optional Stream API, Lyambda expressions, Netty
 - » SQL (MySQL): DB design, DDL/DML commands, subqueries and nested queries, window functions, Join, view, functions, triggers, transactions
 - » Spring Framework: Java EE basics, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Java Persistence API, Spring Data, Thymeleaf, Spring REST, Spring Security, SpEL, AOP, Spring WS, WebSocket, Spring Cloud, Spring Integration, Spring Testing
 - » Algorithms, data structures, architectures, patterns
 - » optional: computer networks & operating systems, Linux work station, bash, GIT, redis, Swagger, liquebase, TomCAT/WildFly, Docker

 $mathred{m} 2021/09 - present$

Frontend development

GeekBrains

♀ Moscow, Russia

- **»** theoretical and practical experience:
 - » HTML5/CSS3/JS learning is ongoing

1998/09–2003/06

Economics and management

Siberian State University of Water Transport

? Novosibirsk, Russia

> Engineer economist

Languages

Russian

native

English

pre-intermediate

Bio

More than a year and a half in Java development. Previously, I have been engaged in analytics and research of the Russia and CIS O&G/OFS markets for more than 13 years. I have rich experience in the development of investment and infrastructure projects. I developed automated economic models. I have worked with large datasets. Actively participated in the development and implementation of ERP and CRM systems. I have developed, automated and implemented reporting formats, conducted staff training. During the training and internship, I mastered OOP skills, studied architectures and design patterns, algorithms and data structures, working with the network and input / output streams, gained practical experience in developing a monolithic MVC project with subsequent optimization for microservice architecture, enriched my experience with data due to the acquired skills in working with relational DBMS and ORM, gained experience in the direction of virtualization and containerization and other related IT areas. Interests: astrophysics, quantum mechanics, programming, AI, cinema and computer games, philosophy, psychology, sports and health. I strive for new knowledge and experience. Looking for Java developer job



